Mm is reaching the tag that has hair color for or something
like that he had such a short brief quite as cutting you frs it wasn't far was
that something was pretty k as yes but just yes he had someone
Beard or something like that I didn't really see the whole and when he got up on the stairs
I had the phone I saw a bit through the holes but I I can't directly take
forward him faces because it was very stressful while I had
panic I phone was waiting for the police so I lost a lot but I will
Remember when I bleed a little this with clothes and stuff I couldn't have directly
be focusing early on that person no but then when i back it was already gone
Yeah just ehm mound color then someone has mine of it
black so it was a dark dark guy it was
Mork but it was yes but is this something you see about the peephole in
the outer door or see d n toward the gate gate since I came in I shouted they
didn't he answer with my neighbor they just comit in mm so i closed quickly d
the balcony and then back then he has been up already at the stairs exactly
outside my door etc. where I saw a bit as I say but I did not have directly
Focus No Prime Crime DSE But you do something special when is up there outside
The door then you notice you do something special when up there no had the phone in hand
I checked in the trunk a bit at him he had the cellphone in his hand but he used to take
away the cellphone as soon as someone comes when he brings out his cellphone so it was not
something special he g only he had the cellphone in his hand much more and then yes
But a little clear control of the pages since you come in and so there etc. How do you mean
that he you said he takes up the cellphone when reaching came when reaching came when reaching then comes then
he takes his cellphone so fast when it is gone when he puts back in his
Pocket so kind of yes and when I get extra concern when I saw this too
clearly yes just that but I had while waiting for the police too they respond and
will come and a little check and check here in the area eh that they have signed under
day that there is foot image and and that person was very much for me new person
new eh there was no one you recognized no no no no such young guy we have
guys who screamed and so d I jumped from the bed checked through the window I
saw some guys outside but when I thought yes it is
Nothing it's quiet fell asleep so I woke up so just as I woke up
eh i saw right next to my window the bed is near the window it was
here is like the camera that the cops are looking through what flying I don't know what
is it called a dr yes m just outside the window when I get really scared then I
Thinking this happened to this I am I did not know did not connect with the police
that it's the ones outside I got very worried I called the police again eh
They sat here long it is we who are out so I think this they were in place
It has happened to everything they have picked all things and the guy and so it is already
everything finished but they were there to have control etc. what what did the girls then
that there is nothing it takes the calm we are here and so there a bit talked briefly with
the girls etc and we are here for us to take little sister move away from home just that
Eh when they fell asleep but I was awake all night yes with the cops etc. just that
you exactly
Ehm I thought about I understood locks it as the police come to your apartment
then and t some pictures and so where the loss and so there you have you put
Label to that is the same day or yes yes but it will be well or yes the same
day if it is the same no because no i saw as i said there are many out i know
not what they are on out no okay it is sure they have done this one
The apartment begins the one we have seen in the picture that there should be some kind
mailbox on the front door etc. is something used for mail or
newspapers or so it is open but there is never coming post in no but it is
what you can do you can go you can avoid yes yes just that and just so we know a little
neighbor in the hall here now d where the room which is from closest to the front door what what
is there for something when it comes to furnished there is actually yes
Since it was a lowering rig before I would throw away so it was a bit of
the bed that was outside just m eh that we would throw otherwise then hang clothes
or shoes or something in the hall no no no no no no something like that no okay
You mean the hall in the house or outside the hall into the apartment closest
your apartment door yes but the hall you are
Obviously that's all there are clothes and hanging clothes and shoes and that
is there wardrobe and that is a lot but just outside it is small box
Is there outside and it is me who put there would throw it was rubbish yes
yeah okay so there was a box outside but in the position though the closet PR yes but that
It is as usual just yes but just eh no but then I probably had no
More questions etc. then we'll see about Mås Questions Yes Thanks Hello like this I also have some
questions eh you told us here initially that you had been in
was there a threat to the family thought F How long before this event
Have you been in contact with the police or with
Bobs the day before they were at home too
eh they told me a little briefly that there is threat picture eh but they were not entirely sure
they didn't know but they just wanted me to inform us it could happen but they have
not invited that we should leave the apartment etc. they have not offer it yet
But they informed us that there is so for me it was very difficult and and take it
here accept that because there were very much questions about why I have
no problems with any eh why v should have there are such threats run my kids etc.
I work my kids have school and job so there is no thing I couldn't
Purpose immediately it f was very difficult so so at this time when you
Can you describe to us how did you experience this event what what like
aroused it for feelings in you it is a lot that is very much indeed and
I think if we first focus on below
The evening can you describe to us how you felt
Then it was a very difficult situation really as I cannot describe is
very messy and scary can s I can sit in dark for two weeks thus
wave and just think and so fast when reaching the fbi the man I become extra worry what is
as happens it may come to happen because I don't know who is trying to burn
m m my child it is very difficult situation it was for me
really so both in the meantime but even afterwards it is so you should understand that you
know this turmoil very much so I've lost everything mm eh I force
Then you think you are like their mother in what way do you notice on them that they
Also are worried about food I thought noticed a lot the lost food that they should
hard to eat ehm so it was just like me and how
How will your children become when they get worried they will be open up and talk
Or do they get closed no no no how how it was much more quiet and
think and as i all said to lose this with patit with not eating food
mm mm you were awake too I usually I noticed on them that they were after all
awake at night but was it silent more in the room bed mm it is hard to sleep
just like me, so I was actually affected the whole
[Music] Family
Mm Thanks then I do not have any more questions for you etc. then we will see if
I don't know the police know yes that was the police told me like me I know
not really the whole story etc. they don't tell you
much yes they told us right about stock but what I know I am very grateful
that my son has thanked me for it did not go on with it a child m
m Then I have no more questions m lawyer Olof no
No no then the hearing is out and we close
by EH and then recording was up and then there is interrogation with Havin Rashid here and
Then Havin is and it is the prosecutor who has requested that you be heard so the prosecutor
will start to ask questions and then your plaintiff will be entered
also get the opportunity to ask you questions and then everyone will
the defenders in turn have the opportunity
Also okay prosecutors may start and lead this for the tube please thank you hello
Hervin Hello We're talking about an event now October 7 to 8th 2023 on Tybblegatan
28 in Örebro I guess you know what event I am talking about then
Yes i would like then to tell you in your own words what yes but what happens completely
Simply what you get to know about about what happens and then also then how you up it
something about why they would pick up that little sister no but so I understood
a little self okay what was it what was it you understood then eh there had been some
Police type the day before MM home with us and eh or I don't remember exactly when
But a few days and said there was a counter -image etc. so I thought it was
because of that yes just that but this with that you were still at home
and that kind of thing was some conscious choice or had you never been given the chance to
leave the apartment no so we got the chance to leave the apartment but it was
One so I wanted to stay at home etc. Okay so that when social services
picked up your little sister then you woke up to a little neighbor and then you saw the whole
The night then or was it something else like you we col
you know then what what happened then no no special i wake up in the morning
No questions no had Skö Bokelund yes a question I just had eh just wondering if you
Have you talked to your brother anything about this threat picture that he has what plays
that is the role of it just with the police tells you so did you ask him how
he was feeling or how you were no it doesn't matter if I talked to mine
brother or not you have nothing with this to do no
G mm shall we see that ollars no thanks no question no then be until and we close
of
the recording and then recording was up and then it is the plaintiff's interrogation here with
Allan Rashid and then Allan will go so that the prosecutor is the one who has
requested that you be interrogated so he will start and ask questions and then so
Will your plaintiff also come up and all the defenders f the opportunity here
But the prosecutor may start and the question should lower the light maybe a little neighbor R there then
Looks better where I think of talking clearly so that it is heard the prosecutor yes
thanks hello belong with b yes you allan this applies to a preparation for rough
murder or preparation for murder on October 7, 2023 on Tylegatan
28 Örebro I would just like to know first what you like to know about
Opportunity No No Thank you No Thank you No then was for the end we st of the recording so
So then we were recording started and then it is before Leon takes Rusic and then eh
So now you have heard here what the prosecutor claims here eh and now you get yourself
Opportunity to comment eh these charges if you want you don't need
say something but you get that opportunity first eh and then come
Prosecutor and ask questions to you and eh targets' entered may have some question
Also eh and the defenders first in defender and then commented the defenders
should be given the opportunity to ask questions but do you want to say something yourself first so
Do you get it yes I have two things to say etc. It is true that I went to eh
Cycle to Ör No What is the name of the Lygatan Shotta thought where I would
setting up a fire I did not have the gasoline with me when I was in place so
regret me eh what is it i i will get shit
because i Figa Animals But I don't want people to think I'm a
murderer it was and the other is that I was not going to answer one question from
Prosecutor I have not been treated fairly because you have to think I woke up
I am awakened at five in the morning then sit in a car several
hours ago i go here i have autism i'm not well i dont feel good v
Sitting here
so yeah so when i was going here so yes i decide i don't think answers to a
only question so right now i intend to be completely silent i understand and that you have
right o and be completely silent but the prosecutor also has the right to ask questions so
will be asked questions and then you can say if you want to answer or not yes
Understand mm good thanks then get the opportunity here please yes thank you
Hi I will ask quite a few questions anyway Leon Eh but before I
Starting with this so I just ask you to consider one thing I have all respect
because you don't want to say anything it is like as you h chair totally okay
but now keep in mind that you risk a very long prison sentence in the end of
this negotiation so you have that mind so you don't miss that bit when
you when choosing your strategy that hearing then first start with we have
looked at phone numbers ending at 5140 that has to a phone that took in
seizure from you this is your
phone since then we have looked at a signal Alas San called S78 is that
Your signal Aljas has looked at a signal that
called dead all have you had contact with those we have looked at a contact that
is called Zakaria Gat which I claim Hams All so today you have had contact with
Örebro you have perceived it all when I claim that
Leon Alfredsson has pulled out of his that he is not with
farther how did it go when the tickets were booked to
Örebro who did this how did the trip go to
Örebro How did you react when you became as it appears signal error and you were forced
change the rotten
H went meeting then in Örebro to whom met and during which
Circumstances How have you received a lighter from the Press Office in it
crew we on the taxi ride to the Ifån
Central Station you have received any money in the said taxi and by
who where do you come since when you step off the taxi
Winston tell us about the conversation you had on the site with Len Alfredsson Hamsa
Kill all other people there are additional
Conversation that you defend the preparation about and in that case where there is
the one it will so out a search or made a search in your phone on
Claim owner Havin Mohammed Rashid Now S made a search
or made a search on your phone on how much money can be put
In that S will be done in the same way a search on Kurdish Fox Ring Fox
The ring and rava
Majid is you who are heard on the audio recording that speaks of fimples
the lock and to burn all
Apartments your defender talked about voluntarily
reversing that you have refrained from committing it is
the deed d i am interested in knowing how went
the
To that was my questions thanks etc. Thank you so much, mother then enters some questions
No thanks i have no questions your defender will have the opportunity
Here no questions no eh we go on here with the lawyers in the order that you
sitting lawyer no questions t lawy none
questions lawyer no thanks lawyer Andersson no questions no then the hearing
End so then recording and then there is interrogation with address Leon Alfredsson
And since Leon now you have heard here what prosecutors say eh and then eh on the same
way like Leon Käg got here so you get the opportunity to first eh say something
yourself if you want you don't have to say anything but you get that opportunity first
And then you will get questions from prosecutors perhaps from the Deputy Deputy and
eh from the other lawyers here first in lawyer and then the others
Lawyers but do you want to say something yourself first here eh no i have nothing
To say no then the prosecution is given the opportunity to ask questions here, etc.
Hi I was going to ask you first if you know Leon Rustic and if so how
eh through a contact okay and v was you got to know hike somewhere it was Leon
So yes Leon what v v was
somewhere on social media okay okay mm just that you are familiar with someone else
here in the hall than smile no
Okay then we know that Leon Rustic for taking a trip from Uddevalla to L B
Also, you know that too, yes now he dm mm can you both a little neighbor what you
then so when i'm maybe 10 meters from the gate eh they shout and serger that it
standing TV outside his door too and then I thought to go back and leave
it and then when i open the door eh so the police
there so it wasn't v so this you have you have gathered some stuff for leon
No have not collected no you have acted so that so no one so that if
one would get stuck in some way that they no did not get away no lean has not said
to me to gather stuff no no no it is you sure yes i have said
that because eh I don't want what is the name of the other guys names no
then there when the police arrived I was stressed etc. but I we agreed that you
have said in police interviews that you are because you sam together Leon's stuff yes
But I have said yes okay and what was it you said what was the reason you
to make it yes but that is not right no exactly and where and what what do you say
lasting reason he has said it was then something special that would
So nothing special so that
is not really right it was just something I said etc. I say that
you had told the police then that it would gather Leon's stuff in case he
would get stuck so that the police or SOS or anyone else would come
ate the stuff yes exactly eh jaus it was yes okay i also say that you have
helped Leon then by doing in the way it has been a support for him one
security for him by looking at his stuff but then you now mean to
Skill against the police that it is not true yes no that is not right no no okay
Okay one eye just gonna make a listing here
that had, as Leon had been in contact with to step then no no had you
any nickname or something no so i can't say i know
So it eh what he tells me and then what I have seen in his phone
it is but i don't know who mm because there is also where i need
probably just look a little neighbor at this it is like
Eh it is the witness hearing now so that it is l a little under spirit circumstances
then of course so so -called soa knows it
402 It has been asked about the apartment owner Leon and that is v
When Leon Alfon became the following I knew he was going to Örebro or
To Stockholm but I don't really know it is pretty good huh yes
Yes then it says like this he also had contact with a guy like he before at
Then there is and this is the summary hearing so it can be
a little performer but there is at 46 just well double check now because you say you
does not remember who it is that has done what has offered L about this that you do not
knew this then then you got the question at 406 after you denied crime then a
suspected interrogation tell me all about this event Örebro so talked about that
Leon then it stands like this v feel hike
Three months ago it was he who offers me to follow this on
The thing is that Leon Rustic offers you to offer you to come along and step
Eh what v did you say eh tuning that leon rustic offers you to follow along and step
So I can't say that he's told me I have only seen
Messages etc. where they said to pick up as many you can it had you seen yes it is
What I have seen but not that he has told me that I will follow with no
It was another guy hambo who offered this job to Leon yes it could be
so yeah but i don't remember no there were people over h who are his reball he on this
The job yes I don't know no no just that but that it may be like that
Yes exactly
Mm and what was it that did you not know anything what
would be done what what Leon would do now as he sat on the train no
I didn't know anything so I said that I didn't want to keep up with no
then yes no because there is a little more precise
information here as as what it should be about as well as that D as I am changed
a little neighbor but still got some information 411 because with you it is also
reaching summary for know man they are a little easier to read about it
themselves on the train I knew nothing I knew nothing and I didn't think so
a lot on it mm just that yes but i
Understand yes
understand this now eh we talked about
Hanko have you had any contact with the Hanko himself yes a little
ehm we talk about for or after the event or both and thus may have
been eh the year before eh and then maybe a little but we have not written with
each other so no okay and what yes in which forums
So do you use which apps instagram instagram sn
Mm just that but you never met so
or no no and what is his name on snap he has some username like me
do not remember
no have you been in touch with N HK and something after
The proportion thus we did not write him after the testimony hearing
Mm eh when i said i had the testimony it was kind of it mm late
have we not written anything so with each other we have sent pictures only
So Snap Pictures Okay We haven't written anything with each other no okay
So that after the event itself, the witness came the hay so it is there apartment
Leon's apartment of that is what I tell you about yes and then you have had
So that is true anyway mm yes but then so
eh then there is another task here on the same Tem as you then said that you
had not received any information from Hamk about what Leon had done for
anything
eh and then it is on p 465 and st for the middle about a conversation
eh where the police have been quoted yes solved a job at the end since he was going to step
Kurdish fox he was going to get 200 salmon cod on one with gasoline can and a
Knife etc. Then we can only take a little short here because it has seen this too
The conversation with inheritance Ran va yes yes eh is you who stout here
What yes did jobs solved until then should step for k yes I wrote it off yes just that and v
bar from had you received this information yes so I knew about it
Mm there was I know it was maybe a month
After mm to step from step to Kurdish fox you would get 200,000
Had you got where did you receive the information I read it on I
the group chat okay is that which f on that or which
my friend etc. and to get there if you go from eh where Leon lives so you have to go
past the police house, etc. and how did he know about it when he saw me at
snap map i have it on because he yes yes yes ok so it was no one
picture on a police sign or reach no it was not a picture or so it was that
he is watching where i was somewhere mm how was
it had Leo on his quick map too yes but he turned off that eh after he
went i think he turned it off when he was in örebro mm eh after he went
Bilf Yes I remember he went car yes eh I saw on snap map he went car but
he did not take a picture or so he went by car okay i saw yes
everything okay but then fte it on the snap map anyway yes so
You mean that you knew to reach where in Örebro so yes I knew he
Was in Örebro but I thought he was going to Stockholm etc. Yes just that
where there is brother I will fucking light electricity on a whole fucking apartment
Yeah there you read that middle yes yes what what did you think about it then i will not
Remember what I was thinking then no eh it was when he was in Örebro yes
Just that yeah yeah eh yes I don't know what to see about
the
No exactly that was he had turned off
snap map when laid yes snap map was off closed i didn't know where h ball no
No exactly what I remember what you answered
This then yes I said film yes just film b and so you can get here
also yes and why did you want Leon to film then I did not want
that he was going to film I wanted to go stressed so he regretted you
couldn't what should I say yes when he was on the way does not
For example, yes but I said it first yes etc. I understand but now now now turns still
Know like that now it is like this, still seriously this now now says in all
fall self to do something yes
No then just after this then he replies to your question film then
Or yes not when I do it so you can do so where I will cod then write
you 248 no brother s leon joha haaha it will see the news has your reply man
and Ma check what a quick on
cod is this something that is part of the lead to try to make Leon not
well that the abomination what do you mean to be when he writes when I will cod yes
and you serve no brother so it sounds from my side like you were trying to get
him to actually implement, the snare brought he should not do it no I
didn't want him to implement it no yes yes you said and you said that too
that you sent notification that he would film for makes the reached stressed then that
he would fine it I buy but just this message it says I will
cod and you say v no yes but what I mean that if the police then he was
afraid that the police saw what we wrote etc. what I mean that if they have already seen
So he has already coded etc. yes but it will come a little later if you say so
Also, but in order to, like when breathing, cod, no, it means that
I perceive all cases as you are trying to encourage to continue but so
I can't say I don't remember no but I don't think I encourage
no no but it's ok what I'm just trying to understand how you
thought I won't try to make it all the opinion but only
But then so but then this continues after the man and checks what snares at
cod so continue there then page 112 film only i want to see yes it is
same as sag to yes so I would like to be stressed
Mm just that you get any answer then from Leon it does not send to the group
or something it is between you and me what is it for the group he is talking about then
No I don't remember this is this signal gray dead everyone and yes it can be
So I don't remember had you access to what is seen there eh I think I
happen so then I know
Not if they die I get the money means he's going to kill someone maybe it is
obvious to reach should yes but I don't know was when
no why no, but that the l who will do it yes the tare he screams it to
me yes yes but just just
that yes your answer then yes but hello fog then send themselves to film
it again then film yes the same cause as before yes
M Then this appears this I send at 2208 here now since it is at
73 yes but where are you sent twice what is
It then yes but what is it then it says how I should film but that's the time
Two I will do it yes and what is it to do then it is like people
Will die me now yes exactly yes just
okay mm but while as n those with the contacts now still so you don't know about
man if you were a support for him or no so I I am barely anything
From that night I was very affected so I can't say no
If I serve that I remember then I lie etc.
Absolutely, but if I now claim like this then that if under the circumstances that
I have told us about now foreign city we have gone very serious crime that one has
that friend on the phone then contact that does not allocate but more a support
So there l with a little more of windows but still there is then I would probably
know the person that it was a support for me you think I deviate from it
that is normal when I reason like that or do I sound reasonable so I understood
not the question no I try to think into Leon's situation where yes no thus
curious just like that then he sends to you 22 23 I'll leave two packages
strawberry outside to mock the strawberry you
know what do you think about it then the whole bit
yes I know
Not because I guess yes then you will be so S that if I am wrong because I guess that
Yet have had some control over this bunch of conflict with shootings and beds
and the like with the strawberry and fox and yes so I do not have very much
check no actually no but maybe a little even or no almost not
I know there has been blasts and stuff like that etc. Yes but I don't know as well
How the conflict starts why no I don't know that much but no but okay yes
but then know about but what what did you think about Leon was like that ended up in it
here the conflict that he suddenly became one of
The actors I didn't think okay
no exactly it remembers what you said at this as i think i'm laughing yes
just yes it is strange to leave strawberries outside a gate yes yes so I
Laughed yes
That's right
It then if we continue 115 then Leon will be spruce a little spruce where they are located
Yes yes H may a her organist and such a yes h had you reach you had any calls or
something during this period is in then obviously one
apartment eh i remember he e send a picture on on
Someone on the couch where he was in the light was the picture that I showed
up the first day when eh what I showed a picture thus
You saw the whole sofa you saw the whole sof okay yes though it was kind of the same picture
Although it was dark yes yes okay I understand
But since then 2247 here you asked but brother should not light no no brother sar
leen v gets the case today no i get the case i know
not yes I just ask yes because it sounds a little spruce that is like trying to
pushes him to do this anyway, but why did nothing happen why do
So I didn't push I just asked he yes I wanted so I wanted to know
What happens I was worried about Leon yes yes I can understand yes so I wanted to
Like knowing what happens yes so we actually see it there
Also the last there when 2248 you will be horned so horned tr but cheated yes yes
okay right there late
so do you have sometime during time here now
Leon went on the train until you know that it is arrested you have
been in contact with the police or something
No and why don't you have it because e or what do you mean to
mean that you have found out of gradually but do you have the same the same
day he went or yes but if s yes exactly but f thought he ate at least i
had for with the police the day after yes but just yes it was when I told you everything
I know yes but then you knew that len said you were yes I read it on
The news yes exactly but I think so before Lean gets arrested when he like
have then gone off by the train and when it is ready for it then gradually that he
scolded a whole fucking apartment and similar that people will die
Yes why don't you contact the police then because I don't want people to go
To my gate and blast my gate no yes and contact the police anonymously then no
I didn't think about it no wasn't thinking about it no dde you at all
about what would happen to people that it was the idea that people would
die i didn't think so much no because it's still pretty badly thinking
If people put life into as well as yes etc.
Then there is actually an obligation to do this that if one now gets
knowledge that a seriously a very serious crime that is committed has
man an obligation as well as eh reveal this r actually
Yeah i have been expelled because i don't want people to go to my gate burst
my gate or kill me m yes since i didn't know one could be anonymous
forward here in court yes yes it is not that you try to protect Leon simply
No after you found out that he himself says that Hanö bought voluntarily
return
But we all even that there is no interrogation when it is without it
New day
Eh yes but now stops thanks mm yes mother react someone
Ask no thanks I have no questions no then the defender will we will stop
The recording
t so then we will see lawyer boklund where then than thanks then I start there prosecuting
does he stop go why you have not reported crime failure to disclose crime
As it is called as you are also suspected of
[Music] eh you you heard the same day as Leon
was arrested by police October 8 eh it is your first interrogation and the police are there
with you we will hear eh the police woman we here then
ehm you eh you tell you there eh that he would go away and
and split for even yes but you don't know where it is Stockholm Örebro or where
somewhere no you don't know against whom no you don't know eh what for weapon to
be used m you have answered here both gun and fire combustible etc. they change
themselves etc. and you do not know against whom no no so if you were to report how
would you be able to report when you don't know who this crime is to be carried out
Against not you know and I don't know where and you don't know where is
Bärt in then in that case after I have gone mm yes but you you do not explain to
the police there why it was like this you no I don't want to say who it was no
I said it was me you yes you said it was you who had
done it and and packed and so m eh but you didn't have bit names in them but you
didn't think yes but I didn't think about what I was stressed then mm is it
real that you then also said that Leon rustic had asked you and take care of
Things Yes I said but that's not true, but it was these eh
two guys who had actually picked it with them mm
[Music] eh you and then we just looked at it
Here eh when you help eh Leon Rustig to get to Örebro think prosecution
is that you have helped with his journey eh what did you know what he would be örebro
you had had a good
relationship you eh thought too
on you were quite long time that went when Leon Rusk pondered on this he had
received this offer to step for even how long
about you think he talks about it one to three weeks etc. reach so and what was
your v hara you him and what do you think during these this time then I have
said he is not worth making it no you advised so way etc. mm and it was
every day he asked so he does and so don't
Mm you and then you yourself when
you man words a train ticket we have seen here eh eh to you you can just tell
briefly how it turned out it was you asked for a tret no i didn't pray for a toet
No that is what he thought he would do but no one has told him he
would do it was just speculation yes so he didn't know either he knew
not
After all, you hear here we have seen the first time on October 8 by the police etc. and
Then you are referred to witness yes etc. and then you told you that there was something
split for the fox yes yes but yes the police do not perceive anything
more about that then you are not heard for one and you are entirely on the loose between
October 8 and November 17 when you are arrested yes etc.
eh you are there many who contact you under it
the time or trying about what then or yes about everything about what you know about it and
what has happened and or do you contact some no it is mostly so that
There were people who under where was somewhere yes
eh the person I did not know from from
Smögen when I told you what had happened etc. yes type
The person so I remember bare that he he looked old yes it is a man or
woman eh a man yes do you remember something about appearance or something else yes he had
no hair no hair any more details it was kind so yeah beard i think so
beard yes yes you talk about ethnicity perceive him
as Swedish or as as
foreign even then in the same interrogation so we had to ask about it so I was at the top of
Page 423 Have you described this with old and scary and then you say he
did not look swedish either yes no exactly he looked a little more murk yes you have then
said he was
brown you know something or how do you perceive situation
What is this for a person
one has shown that I have written to any girl on instagram that I sent
to her my old snap I have sent so I sent her my
old snap because I don't want to give her my what is the new snap then on
new snap I have only so few people who are familiar and so not as before I
had kind of 500 people people I didn't know and so yes on the new snap I
had only people I knew and my girlfriend then and my girlfriend she has what
is it called access to she has read the north to my new snap so she usually
Go through my new snap and check if I write with other girls and stuff like that
When h where the girl asked about my snap I sent this one my old one in case
and I ask why I didn't send my new and thus just old it was
That's why I sent old for my girl usually go through my snab and check for
I write with other girls and I usually use my old snap myself
So then when I usually go in write with other girls and since I have too
formed on my old snap that I usually go in and so use this yes try
Get hold of yes then when it comes to this crime so I knew
nothing about this I had nothing with this to do it was then it
the day after l voice was arrested when I got a call time in the morning such as
Man showed at 09 something I don't remember exactly but yes I got
A call of a number that had not saved on my phone so I replied
I asked what is the name of the person I just who is it and since it was Leon
for something or if he has done something so he only you can check
Internet search for it so I searched that picture from then what is it called
The article on my phone man has found out what is it called telephone emptying it is
from there eh I have the picture from what is the name of the act itself and
the one from there I saw that it was enon person who had been what is it called
arrested for general fuel when it was the present that was then for I
didn't even know what it means so i didn't think so much about it after
I loos on I don't know if it was right after or later in the day then
Because Leon Alfredsson told me this with that my number through signal then
I wanted to check so I downloaded signal on my phone and I wrote my
number i tried to log in m it did not go i think it might be so that
Been finished and posted on August 1st so why I have emojis thus
It was just an emoji I chose I have nothing with this conflict that
do or what gang I so I do not even belong to this conflict
or fst and so small have said I do not want to be involved in that
So I would not show to people that I belong to any network o so
because people would see that where it would hit me my family and so
Why should I show myself and r emoji the only thing I thought about I wanted to
only part joint i had in hand because i have v nam named family members on
Instagram so I put this emojin by the hand as you see in the picture it is there
I do not let it be so that I will be over my head or somewhere and
so like sinol I am going to be at hand because part jint had in hand and then
to folkrot or any other k network these images they are taken from tiktok and
What is it called Instagram it from social media and you see it too
Look at the picture so then why I have it just on
My phone It is no wonder, so almost all young people in the whole of Sweden have
It on your phone and you follow what you read on news every day
What happens in Sweden thus this wave of violence then that e gates are blown up and
So like and I follow myself this conflict I have so I have yes
A little control over it not so much but I usually follow it on social media
Because it is rapping and so as is involved I usually listen to this one
the rapper I usually follow it so that's why I have it on my phone and yes late
It was also another I wanted to comment on that was this with that
there is something now in the car you will see you will see for times worse this so
I just won't do anything I did nothing since they pulled that one
the card yes you resist even though it made no resistance they jump on me
from nowhere so it was just the had you say and one to the thing I will
Continue also be quiet I do not know what is it called eh will be quiet
Prosecutors can ask their questions and then I also know that this is serious
So brat as I suspected why not wanting to mention this person
who have to my snapchat and number so i don't want names in him
Because you know for yourself what it is, so it is nothing strange with the people they
get shot they get dead they get blasted for such things to be named
or man b out any person i don't want to get involved in anything i have
not with this conflict to do or reach some of the crime that
do I don't want to expose my family to proceed so I hope you understand and
respect what I will not name that person or any other yes is
Clearly thank you so much then prosecution should be given the opportunity to ask questions here etc. Thank you
The hello I was just thinking about asking you first you have during the police interrogations that held
with you exploited your right not to answer any questions or
How it is totally okay that you don't say anything but go I have to get
Asking Questions R St question is true that it does not say on
some questions on Len if you don't want to comment so you can just say none
comment can no no i will keep being quiet on yes okay yeah okay
So you are not going to answer that question now yes but on f may ask questions and about Ham
understand it is the snap account zeria gat it is yours
Quick contact about
this
signal contact that had borrowed
the telephone number about the explanation for the loan of
Signal Contact Phone Number Tie as to why he then needs to borrow
borrow the snap account as well where one does not have that type of eligibility requirement in order to
able to use snap you have to even e a phone this
the friend what is the name of this friend that
is meant how is it that this signal or sorry sn's
chat traffic that then this unknown friend would have committed
or lied behind it there is a shovel in your
phone which then not which then not the conversations
do if it is now that it is not you who used
the one we will come to these two accounts
used in parallel with each other with the same
content thus in large parts that is, both your signal button
do not want to reach some kind of security regarding your own
Conversations your contacts
Although an old account which contacts did you have with Leon
Rustic at HVBhemmet
the conversation with Leon Alfsson you have threatened him with some time the same with
This is that you know where he lives somewhere for the guys to give up on him
sent his father's old address or
Similar have reached others who knew had that you had had a conversation
with Leon Alfredsson so that it is somehow reasonable for someone else
person could have done this in that case and in that case
who foxes symbol why do you send it the same
talking about
Today we'll see I'll just double check what you said before
Even if you are now so afraid to be associated with the Fox network as you actually did
As you said it was then it turns out that you are so careful that you
sitting with what at least I interpret as a rä symbol on your left hand in
photographs that you yourself say you have shared with
of mm
Thanks thank you so much then your defense or we will go for the go on for forgetting here
Well, no thanks no questions no then you should defend for opportunity here please
Yes I was going to ask Hansa you reply if you want but prosecution mentioned this one
the audio file where it is mentioned to step and I can for your knowledge so that it happens
Two weeks after e rus understand this event, you want to say something about
It yes, exactly this thing this thing does not have with this goal
And then Sandra now for this goes in the same way as for the others here to
you first get the opportunity to say anything here if you want if it is as
Prosecutors claim that you have done eh and then the prosecution will have the opportunity to
Ask questions and goals know the tree and then all the defenders EH will first
infes defend and then they tender yes crime lasts are allowed to turn it off
that sounds for it has been pipit all morning has done so attempts and
and pull down the volume as much as possible so but now we'll see you want to say
Something yourself first here so there is nothing that really concerns the goal
But I just want to emphasize that I have never taken heroin in my life that
is important to me that it arrives etc. it hears a little for come a little near
the microphone so where I know then said you have never taken heroin so that
about the friend and why should you do this no it was nothing special at all
would come h so get a friend he just said mm there was nothing strange at all
mm he has set up and let me be allowed to live with him then but feel acquaintance to
him and so there so there was no weirdness no f they speak none
weirdness where I claim that you are interrogation early and told it it was
A friend of you who would come no friend yeah yeah okay okay and that i said
from the beginning too okay just right
What I thought we might be able to take it right away so it gets clarified
Page 569 Here mentioned a task eh it g that summary in itself
But in the middle here, the question if you remembered you would meet someone it
day and then we talk on October 7 when m eh then the answer is the police have
intention but it is easy to lose if you are out and make stuff small
criminal things deeds but means that you understood that this is
about crime that was what one did no it was not so i said now
Do you distort my sentences yes no I just ask but it wore it
appreciated I don't know what other people do on their
leisure this with that you were afraid to leave DNA on the lighter it is after all
something that I claim has not come up with anything for police with has done it
was the first thing i said j jaar i history because i don't want to
My friend is going to get involved in this and it is for my own safety now I
not with fix take me now prime.se
Ok
For sorry it's just indications everything it just indications yes
okay [music]
Mm but i think like this now you have any control over if Daniel was something in your
apartment if when you were not there no I have not
No i had no key i can't lock you have asked your friend anything about
This then how it is related to no I have not why do you not have it why
would I therefore be suspected of crime which you know after
Like the police fuk on yes but I have already heard everything from my friend
and what did you hear from your friend then we need we don't have to go into it we
can leave my friend outside it mm Although you do not talk about him anymore without
just about the information that you have provided to you that is, what you have known to
No just like that then we have some searches too
on this event on your phone thus quite late after the incident is
It no wonder what is it strange about it yes but tell me what should
I tell me why were you why not that is what is it I would
prove h saying this is what you are suspected of crime I claim that you have done
one more divorced to Medh for preparation for murder yes I know I have taken it
And of course I wonder why you have sought information for this
the incident that you are suspected of that makes you sit here today yes I know
not you know don't believe yourself no you may not set you may not
ask questions back and the prosecutor is trying to formulate questions and then so
Do you choose whether or not to answer so that prosecutors try to formulate questions
And and Sandra Petterson does not ask questions back on the prosecution why
Have you searched for information about the one I knew I was withdrawn in that
m and I knew my ex -man was detained for that so it is clear about
one is interested and wonders what it is
where it says it will cod soon it means
Nothing means nothing no it means nothing i sit here five
months later or how but it doesn't say i'm prime.se have you
cod now yes apparently I have r because i sit here after five
months okay okay then so cod it doesn't mean that
one is guilty in any way one can cod innocent as well
Okay but if you get suspected of crime you have coded then or are to be judged
first but you cod you do when you get locked up if you become
arrested in i i i a lob it does not mean that you owe no man can
cod as innocent mm during the time as you before you were arrested after the event
So do you have after I think change phone numbers then so you have swap
Phone Numba wand once va according to can see not even twice yes why
have you done it as it is not something strange I change the phone to
phone numbers as often i change lingerie so it always has been for
me why is it so because they get stolen they disappear i drop them
The kids have Sunder them etc. Okay I understand but just that it happens
so closely related to this event with something somewhat active choice only one
pure coincidence yes just a pure coincidence and I wish and this so with the phase in hand
so had I wanted to have the phone left etc that I had then and why had
you wanted it then because I had a prove even more of my virginity in this
Okay what had we found then nothing okay that is exactly what is the thing ie
found as little as this time okay mm
and why do you stay away from the police where because i put to do be ill
I didn't stay away I was sick but you sat if saying so here is
real or not really that you sat hidden in a meat
cabinet the police lit on me now listen now is the way i got to lie two
days in my own urine in the arrest of the police because I was so bad I had
infection of the spine I sat waiting for my
Mom she was going to drive me to urgently it's nothing strange that I stay
from the police when I am as sick as I was I was not even able to go go
up on and be interrogated I had to lie there in that room for two days before
When I got to go to the doctor where I was also hospitalized etc. Okay so it is
your illness as g that you are sitting hidden in the kitchen cabinet I also had contact with
got to touch most of what is relevant about
you ehm you got more questions about eh
your interrogations and so we start it when you touched something when you were arrested yes eh can
you tell us anything about your condition your health condition and how
had been the time before the police eh it wasn't good I was bedridden in two
months m simply i had kidneybäck infection and so i had an infection in
the spine while the doctor missed etc so I was in to urgently when I went
Ambulance in the first time etc. I understand on what you told you have followed
reporting about this mm eh when and how did you realize that your ex -man Daniel
where was deprived of liberty pretty fast yes my friend called me yes pretty fast yes
is it only then that you get to know about it when he is already
Liberty now I did not understand it was then in Samand with the fact that he was
detainee as you understood it was
Just then eh you tell you that it will be until early December
Eh what have you known and what have you had an idea of the police's interest in
For you as we know, after all, in this investigation is there, so I have understood
that they have wanted to have me eh on interrogation yes eh but I didn't think it was
that I was as seriously involved as I am because one time for it
Booked interrogation before I was sick so it was quite long between the dates
from when at the hearing would be sky so you have known and you have been called
to to police interrogation yes through contact with the police yes yoke you and you mentioned so
just so it becomes clear and through contact with the police you and with me
ehm you tell you about your illness and we can too
eh backwards you have told you and it appears that you have a
abuse problems bit made clear that it did not include heroin but during
this period around the crime and until you seize how was it with
With the situation of your abuse then I am abusing Ann
And it was pretty partly so I am celebrating years and partly so my daughter is celebrating years in
the same vein yes and then i usually crap down right really for i i
cannot with the dates really the current day when at the beginning of October 7
Yes you will not have declared that you want to answer questions about that person
as who contact you about this eh but if I say this person he has
also a connection to to that side of your life that deals with abuse and
so eh prosecutors interest so for the question you they about v and lend an apartment
based on the basis of your life and your situation
eh this is a common or unusual phenomenon common it is very common
Can you tell us and explain how has it been in your life around accommodation and
Housing So I have been homeless for eight years yes eh and borrowed sofer here
and was so we at me and Daniel we stayed well on reach off toilet for three months believe
I eh and so I showed even if you tell in my own words at this
The time so eh I told you that you were not waving so
much in this apartment what did you spend your daily rest during those
here hawk and x yes now i did not hear in the brickebacken at my ex okay and yours
ex as we stick to eh There is there is one a conversation that I have
shown yes there is a name amigo yes it is the person who yes yes in time
for this crime and its before eh had you resumed a relationship
Then ehm
around Daniel Eh after you tell you that you
broke what contacts have occurred between you and Daniel after that no one
at all prime.se and the current day it s there were some contacts
No did you have any knowledge of what the prosecutor claims EH that Daniel has
done in relation to gasoline cans no so I know after all
Not I am not sure that exactly that day because my neighbor does not
knew but i know he has been there and threw out Daniel someday m
If the apartment as he has told this
The apartment can tell you about circumstance to it how long do you have
had that apartment since September yes and eh have lived in the apartment for some time
Yeah with me earlier before i took over it yes but he pulled there reach someone
time in early September so he was not at home when I got home one day
eh you touched it but in terms of access to the apartment eh how has
It has been with it to be able to access the apartment how there are many who
the preliminary investigation into what you said said about that you remember what you said in
Your first interrogation question again did not understand you received
questions about why you have handled the tänan on it
ways that you do remember what you told you then yes that I am careful etc.
eh considering that the prosecutor read up and who has said later for I would
want to reproduce then if you don't remember exactly why picks up the tän so for
I am careful if I don't know people how do you mean I don't know what
my stuff ends up i'm just careful of myself because i live that life that
I do I don't know what lit harbor since I don't know the man I know
not what he does and don't do I do not draw on people etc. it may be true that you
have said so in the first hearing we'll see which side was it yes sorry I
did not reproduce it but this is on page 553 and it is apart from eh it
initial short interrogation the first longer hearing held with Sandra
Pettersson wherever is there somewhere about the page is almost at the bottom
Page 554 This is the third question from the bottom why do you pick up the lighter so it
subsequent question how does mean
you after Sandra showed a picture from Resby then yes just yes now I am
Map
ehm you come to the apartment you have any idea you describe there that
You show the apartment and show around MM you have any idea of how long
you find yourself five minutes max yes you and leon between down how do you talk
What contact do you get during the taxi ride and where no it was nothing eh I am
very shy off with mm eh he has autism what has been stated now so it
was nothing we greeted well to each other we met up and then there was no one there
mm he asked if a lighter etc. So you have noticed in or connection
to the apartment something of what is present here have you seen or
noticed something out of gasoline cans or nothing that
occurs a packet of strawberries you have observed something like that
so it may have been there but there is nothing i react
on after you have left Leon where what do you then go to Amigo to Amigo yes
tillack my Duur you get you there yes I take bus first to the back to
Central Station and then I pick up my bike I had st there
Yes thank you so much then the other defenders should have the opportunity Larsson no
Thank you no thanks thank you so thank you yes may lean back a little thank you so much hello
SRA Hello I have some questions this with with heroin that Daniel started using
heroin it was in September you said yes and I understood it as it was a bit
of a red line for you yes yes it is your view that Daniel is so deep in
the abuse that he starts with heroin then it is pretty bad yes it is not
would you say it is his main feature in normal cases yes in ordinary cases but
Not when we do with the item no so this was really a decline in
The abuse can be said so yes eh then the prosecutor has asked a lot of questions about it
Here the friend who both lending out your apartment yes but eh is not that you
Don't know how Daniel got involved in this no I have no idea how
Daniel got involved without the only pure conclusions from my s yes speculation
can you say that price friend has not told it that he has involved
Sometime around at some point somewhere around at least yes okay
Eh yeah exactly what i understand then so was this
with yes exactly what it was the one when it had you rode answered
[Music] ehm no but it was ok it was all
Thanks mm ty from the defense as no then is
the interrogation end and we turn off
The recording so we have input and then there is a hearing with Daniel
Pettersson here when Daniel then comes to the same way as for the others here
that you first have the opportunity to say something yourself first if you want
don't need it but you get that opportunity first and then you will
get questions from the prosecutor and perhaps from the target tree and eh then will
the defenders have the opportunity also your defender will have the opportunity first yes
But do you want to say something yourself first about what is said here yes
So what should I start
Eh i can start by wake up on a toilet prime crime
DSE Because I was I am, as I said, homeless and wake up reach toilet was
and yes eh has been awake for a very long time and
just walked around eh i wake up to the toilet and just thought another one day in
this fucking life eh no
[Music] so
Yeah so I just should take the day of the day as well as do what you usually do when you
the person just said but offered m yes some drugs if i could help
with cases I just thought damn what nice it
Will be this day already free drugs I thought
just so yes I got some cash from him and then he said he would have
And then I cycle off and bought the stuff and eh mucked up again later
on Olof Palme's peat and fined stuff and then I went to the nearest toilet and
yeah struck in with the drugs and then it was yes then hang with it that is it me
Has so
mm Thank you so much m then go to possibly ask questions to you here m
just that and that man it was it was a whole new acquaintance so yes completely
random mm what was it he said you would do when you got what was it you
The Macken Okay so that's why you go to the other maen on Östermalm's plan
or Österplan is called S's yes mm just okay so that is why you go
cyclary there then so it is why you cycle right there then to yes that
So was it just cycled there that
was like my body just went so there so drove by itself etc. yes but
It is not that you chose the needle in another place so as not to wake up
much attention up no, for no no what did you have that can with
gasoline and so when it was on the east floor then was that can with gasoline as you
You bought at Södermalm's bag I have a bag on one bag is my home
Like then it is clothes and stuff so you have bags and stuff after all
when cycling around yes and is home yes so they are in the bag okay
Mm just that mm and how long did you take all this as i had no mobile
or clock so i don't know no yes when you bought on the east floor then what do you
then then v in other place yes just yes
cycled back up to Olof Palme where we met so we just shifted yes late
Went we ate whose hobb was he left there when you or was he there in place when
you got there or yes he was already there yes okay got it approved then what you bought
Was that where you would do yes I got the drugs so yes
Because it feels a bit neighbor as a coincidence how much ethanol you shop as looking
up bottle as i understand it va or have understood it wrong that you are forced to look
up mortgage bottles or bottle to the speech we must have something to pour out
Like yes it was then then I usually root for pledged money yes but was it
Just one and a half liters of zero you would buy it I don't really remember
It was just there so okay okay as I said I'm in
severe abuse during this period so it is very foggy mm it is
Almost so that I don't feel good either, it's almost like that I don't
want to live mm mm and when you get when you hand over then d gasoline and
The ethanol is it when you get yes we simply change then I jump on the bike and
just pulls to the nearest public toilet mm
m and how much money represents this drug approximately f yes what can
it be what was it 2 g about what could it be
400 400 approximately mm mm and this by getting SEK 400 approximately
is paid for shopping some gasoline and a little ethanol it feels like pretty good
That's how you started the day yes yes is it correct Daniel that you are you are multimix
users so to speak yes my drugs are amphetamine and opiates heroin and stuff
where yes yes and you said that happens not infrequently to
people come up and ask are there somewhere to shop or about if you
have it is the drug you mean then yes exactly would you say that is visible on you a
Ordinary day that you are homeless you are addicts yes it can yes it can come
front people in with outside business or whatever the hell etc I don't know I
have such body language maybe I do not know etc. and I understand right to
Södermalmsplan The first Macken OKQ8 mm They did not have ethanol at all it was real
Yes it wasn't that you chose to buy ethanol where there was no ethanol
No there was nothing was ethanol part of the order on this guy at ol
and so that it is clearly these gloves you said you had not
had with them to do have you seen them before as before you got to see them in
the preliminary investigation no no and this with you to have become
out thrown you sanda's apartment and there you have investigated and stuffed with not
come somewhere you have been ejected from Sandra's apartment no
no in normal cases we we had a little reverse your staff I was before
in the week n went into your personal circumstances you are convicted of a little
Small crimes earlier yes in drugs It is a bit of an attack thus small thefts and so
there but all that has been about to be able to see it my abuse etc. I
I note that you do not misunderstand serious crime earlier it is small
stuff is related to the abuse yes abuse clear day
thus hunger soul fed v anyway as it is the kind of crime you have
dealt with yes yes thank you no more questions thank you so much adart larsson no thanks
Attorney Atten No Thank you lawyer Boklund No Thanks Adat Andersson No Thank you
No nothing more superficial then the hearing is out and we turn off recording
lasting recording started and then the testimony is with Mats Rosin and that
is the prosecutor sitting here closest who has requested you to be interrogated so he
will start to ask questions and then the plaintiff's assistant may have someone
Ask to ask and then the defense lawyers come in turn
Here and have the opportunity to ask you questions too
Start here, yes, but thank you to just mention first that this applies then the 7
October not the 8 I sow wrong in proof the task j the same applies to the above Anna
then the cold as well as mst food you have talked to the police previous interrogation
regarding the intake that you would apparently have been made near your
i just in but it didn't feel so good then so yes i went leave the laundry and
So I went out again and the wig was around the block mm and then
went back in and hold in the stairwell and then then put cigarette butts in the lock
on the door etc. and so it could not be locked ok so it stood down then yes exactly
Mm and then I went and then checked in the stairwell if he was left etc I thought
If one were to burglary in the wind or something like that there yes just
it was he left forgive he was left then how hot was he left when you said it
would check if he was left yes yes he was not left then trpp house anyway
No no just that mm okay you made any other observance regarding
This eh n
More I am just going to double check so it's not something like yes I don't get on
seven first time to ti okay s mm okay mm and do you have any perception
some memory today how he looked about that clothes or similar yes okay
Not like this don't remember the face but I remember v that it was
dark dark clothes mm and yes dark
dark or hat or cap m dark just that
Mm then yes foreign mm mm just that did you see some
marks on clothes or something like that loan in memory it was nothing I
thought of no you saw anything about how he came to
the place or left the place or so I if you had I saw nothing about it
No he was just outside mm just that and he was going to his grandmother's or grandmother
Grandma said yes just that and you you said that because you felt a little bit
For us what happens to those fimples yes I pick them out yes and after that
works locks then yes you need something to get into the stairs when
it is locked eh after ten needed a tag please
a lot were the questions I had but it is possible to come in right then it went to
come in another way too yeah like yes the family in question v
tell yes they stuck in eh a tray because the lock was a bit raised so you could
get into this
the manner stuck a breed in the lock for it would work or whatever n man
Powers up control because it was a little break s st
burglary attempt at where you could insert a credit card and poke up lock fol
they are the information Mats have you told about this to the police no I have
Forgot it you came on today I am coming on now when you ask
Yes you I thought like this eh if i summarize it so your story is
so this is that this person puts cigarette fimps the door lock yes for
that the door lock should not work yes you remove the cigarette fimps etc. I say that
The door lock works the door is closed the door is closed yes to get into
the stairs you need thanks true yes thank you very much
Yes, so no questions had Skö Bokelund no thanks to SK Olofs had brows Andersson no
Thank you no then is for the ear end and we turn off
We also recording recording then recording and then there was a witness hearing here
with Sebastian Anserius and it is the prosecutor who has requested here that you should
If he is interrogated he will start and ask questions and then the target tree will come and
All the defenders also get that opportunity here but the prosecutor may begin
Well thank you very much Hi Sebastian Hello this is true you really have
written three pieces of pm that I have been invoked and that applies then to your
Observations from Tylegatan here early in the morning of October 8, 2023 in Samand
one at a hedge under a tree right in height with number 28
eh shortly thereafter eh goes the same person left go forward with
This white bag that hung from the handlebar eh and posts some items
just outside the entrance to the stairwell number 28 when mm eh on a stone paving
where eh then goes back to the bike eh where he parks it under the tree eh and
eh yes reside where eh eh i start to work my way forward eh in conjunction
with this eh and it is dark outside eh but
eh just what could it be five feet away from him maybe i'm very close
eh so i announce that police are there and that he's going to show his hands eh was on he
gets up from this shade there under the tree
eh sees gets very surprised looks around and then so tries to run
somewhat flammable or explosive etc. mainly flammable as mm was based
the circumstances of the scene now came those objects have been there already when
the parked bike or how do you look at it
thing eh no that they
Eh that we had seen we had I had been there for a good while and look there
eh so I would say that and we had also moved in the area so it had
stood a yes one than a pet bottle I could very well have missed but not
the red dunken no it had I seen etc. you have any idea how
long time it takes roughly from the time he comes to the place from that it
decides to intervene eh yes it goes pretty fast eh
comes cycling there and turns pretty straight away then everything happens in a
dense foals so from seeing him come cycling to
that he is actually arrested so one and a half minutes about maybe mm it goes
fast how long had you been at the site approximately and observed or
scouted as it is called
So at that particular position, then M had against the same gate if you say so
it v made yes just that yes but it had
were a few hours anyway etc. there would have been more people who heard in or
Had there been any somin except the gate time you stood there
Eh i know there were people moving outside but never to ell
Port without the gates letters I want to remember etc. Okay and but I am etc. but gates
Blö did you say yes exactly mm What was it that made the decision to intervene against
This person then eh no but the behavior
eh both tien on the day and eh eh how he looks around even before he turned
eh made the gut feeling said it was interesting and then when he puts
themselves in yes in the darkest place but still near
Any case no I understand how long was it thought you would stay
left about then on the spot it was like all night or was it
Mm yes v what i know we had no eh
eh restriction set or end time no it was good no but then exactly that i
thought about what has been spoken a little bit about fimples and dishes and the like so
The question is is there any one has been any person who has stood and smoked there
As you have seen eh not as I have seen no no and it
Here the person arrested have you seen any signs that he would have smoked or
handled cigarettes in some way
Eh yeah i know he i know he had liters on
Eh i can't remember now eh if he had cigarettes on but we
Wrote up eh eh what was found on him and
Things were also seized so it should be stated there etc. Yes but it does it he
cycling until he was arrested so he didn't smoke anyway but liters I know
that he was wearing etc. yes but what good but then I'm done anyway then thanks
Mm Thank you so much then we'll see if Morä has any question here no thanks I have
No questions no then we take the lawyers here lawyer Larsson no thanks no questions
no questions please thank you no thanks no then is for the ear
end and we turn off the recording then I have to thank
You then recording was once and D Witness interrogation here with Anna Karlen Eh
and it is the prosecutor who sits here who has requested you to be interrogated so he
will get to start and ask questions m and then the plaintiff will get the tree
Also get the same opportunity and then the defense lawyers EH will come in turn
order also get that opportunity here m eh i see you brought out some paper
where what you usually usually do as a head not like this so put away there a little neighbor
As long as we get so that but prosecution will start to stand questions here m
can you observe so i don't think i see
The hair wonders if it is hood on or if it is but
mm spontaneous yes no I dare not really say it no but it is quiet you
eh just has his behavior in general is
that something that feels like feels like web or could it been
Anyone that but only that he stood in an inappropriate place right then
we experienced or I experienced like he was nervous it was like wandered
A little off and on and thus it felt like yes but nervous in the behavior etc.
Eh so M understands just that it said he followed someone reaching who lives there
inside the stairwell has any idea of how that person looked up it as
I said the one who lived in the house then no but long eh and kind of ward jacket on
or something with reflexes on just the dirty type yes but work pants something
such boots etc. mm just that
ehm just about when you see that guy in the tpp house you get any contact
or something then or no no no i don't know if he sees us like we
just walked by and then we turned and went back as well and saw that there was a
person there so then we thought we would not go in no exactly no but what should
When I get answers to my questions anyway etc. Thank you so much then Mother's Bet
Träde gets the opportunity yes thank you also some questions you eh you told you here
about the threat picture that you got it there was against the family and contacts only
Too clear debt who in the family is what you have contact with it is the mother in
The family that I have contact with the mother etc. and
You also told us here that eh eh it was a sequence where you see that
A neighbor goes in and that a person follows in and that you then talk to
The family again etc. eh tells the mother about it is the mother you talk to too m mm
call the police directly etc. and eh then I wonder too have you had
any more contact with the mother or someone else in the family after this
The event
Yes we had a follow -up call the day
After who participated in the conversation it was me and mom who talked then etc.
eh just to, like yes but tune in to the way it became and that they are protected
everyone and how was her state of mind then no but stressed
or but like worried etc. she told me something about how they
The other families had reacted to what has happened to what they were aware
If no then I think we just talk about as well as her experience and
since the smallest child as you say the one we had contact around it was
the conversation revolved around MM and as well as to make sure they all had come
The home for a period eh is something you know about yes yes but
I know then and then at least that they no one was left in after yes then I know
Not after the Deten but the day after I know at least etc. Thank you then I do not have
Something m mm Thank you so much then eh the lawyers here f opportunity to law
Larsson No Thank you lawyer Attas NO Thanks to Lawyer B No Thank you No No Thank you No
then the fores are over we turn off even now and then the recording was up and running
And then there is a testimony here with Magnus laid and it is the prosecutor who has
know that you will be interrogated you will see him soon here in the picture so he will get
Start asking questions to you and then eh will be entitled and the different
The lawyers here will have the opportunity to ask questions too but go F Start well
Thank you hello hi you work as a police officer I understood as yes it is true yes v good it
Here applies to your observations on Tylegatan in Örebro on the morning of October 8, 2023
knows what event I am talking about then yes then I would like you to tell
first with your own words about what you see what happens on the spot then then maybe I have
which is not at the moment or then can see what it is
eh then he goes back to his bike that stands a few meters away under a tree
and starts to do something where he sits down crouches down and does
something where eh then my colleague runs out and
together with other colleagues who are there
Eh yes grabs this person and I stand in this building and look
All the time because we leave some equipment there so I can't leave
Mm that's probably what I remember by that particular event etc. Absolutely great it is
just a control question there so there is no misunderstanding there when you
says it sees something red in the bicycle basket and that it sees a bag on
The board we talk about by definition different objects as yes exactly the bike basket sits
after all on the board and there is something red in the bike basket and then is
it a white plastic bag then as it says Willis on if I don't miss m on as
hanging on the board just what good it was the questions I have anyway thanks
Thank you so much then goals Senbet Tervare will have the opportunity here no thanks I have no
Question no then the defenders should have the opportunity here ad Larsson No Thank you
Questions Ol H Andersson No Thank you no is the end and we turn off
the recording with sound here only and then the recording was up and then it is
thus bitness interrogation here with Helena Malmeling and it is the prosecutor who has
requested that you be interrogated he will start asking questions and then will
Enter gets the opportunity and then eh all the defense lawyers in turn
Here m but but the prosecutor may start thanks thank you uh thank you hello you you
Works as a police officer's overstam Yes it is true yes and this
applies to your observations then in connection with
The house search on Fjällvägen in Uddevalla on October 8, 2023 you know which
Event I am talking about then yes but I got help from my prom memorial
be good but you can v tell yourself then first what yes but what happens
What observations are made for this occasion so maybe I put some
supplementary questions on it late yes thank you eh i together with colleague then make a
Husak on Fjällvägen 28E Eh and the apartment then at
the ground floor eh eh and even then in associated storage then on the same plane
Eh and this store is empty and there is a bathtub in I in this
the storage room but nothing else eh you are doing some kind of work
with ventilation drums in in itself
the apartment there so yes it looks a bit like a construction site to some extent in
and so on ehm and
eh yes we are in this one and always now we just this assignment we have
really no more knowledge that we will then make the house the case for
eh in Uddevalla we do not own the case but the Örebro case and we have very
scarce information in what has otherwise happened but we will do h.
at least mm ehm it is the apartment itself so it is
A little disorder in this apartment as there is some clothes holes and noise eh
There is a lot of disk there is a little flip boxes eh eh it says a big tvl
Åda in the apartment and no television but we get it later that it stands after all
Outside the apartment m When we do house things, we always lock the apartments
so that no one then comes in eh but all of a sudden a person comes into
the apartment and then with own key eh and we identify this person
eh no weirdness he behaves in a good and and pleasant way toward
us eh and his name is Leon then
Alfredsson he had no identification with him there without we do
Dataslayer
[Music]
Even a hearing with him that is documented on who sees dies then
ehm he then demonstrates that he has exhibited this TV for a one -camera
would pick up this TV later and it is then eh under a lake and that
is just outside in the stairwell and there is also a one bag and this one
The contents of the bag is, among other things, a black suit a white shirt a white tie
and there were some fine shoes there in size 41 Eh a confirmation Bible etc. and h
computer in a one computer bag eh then there was also some empty patrol sleeve there and that
Here, after all, EH is taken and we use Vilh Skar Le he would like to
look in this bag but he must not do it because he wonders if it was
something that belonged to him but but VSK can then seize it
eh to named eh we he knew that his friend then
Leon Kg Rik was arrested there and that information he had received from
Media and yes I thought it felt a little unclear why this one
the bag was packed with all belongings and why it was then
a one suit and a Bible and eh yes with white tie and a cartridge sleeve it was yes
A little unusual things I think eh then there were probably two mobile phones
there that was out some older model and some shaver but they cannot
say that I remember if it lay in that bag or if he wore them in
jacket or otherwise I don't know that but it was there was some kind
information about like who would have packed this bag yes I took it
Like that it was Leon Alfredsson then who would have packed down some things
as which would then be eh eh good
eh for for eh to his friend then etc. so it was he who had exhibited it was
So as I perceived yes just that
ehm and the friend was it v who was it was it was located insered or where someone
other who was intended no no the buddy as he had
packed the bag and so was his clothes and so on in this one
The bag it was Leo he I call Leo Käg rustic then just that
just
ehm said something about why he now maybe we will not be on for but say
anything about why he has packed this bag then what the purpose
with yes eh eh I for me and wrote it
somewhere in either in the ear
penny because i can't pick it out do you do it because it says there on page 83 yes
I don't have the page references in those eh because I don't have the preliminary investigation
in front of me there but yes but he says it thinks that witness should not look in
the hearing there without it without it you may try if you don't remember then you get
so try to put away pap there and is it that the lawyer may ask a question and
If you do not remember then the lawyer must consider whether to request to be read
up here eh but have i written then in the interview
So it was as he said in the interrogation etc.
Eh but what I remember it was that Leon Alfredsson in interrogation says that
he had been waiting to get some kind of assignment so he was like ready to
go to go where would he go you mean no sorry leon
The hearing should be
Secret no it is not that the hearing should be secret but but Leon Alfredsson
Don't want to stand for in interrogation who this one
the client is no, there is something mentioned about it
clients yes i leon he he is the pictures from an instagram account
eh on a guy who is then called the account is Hanko at Insta this guy will
hot hamsa and it should be this eh hamsa
then as who has given the mission itself it is something like Leon that
says my yes I show pictures and they have also attached
the investigation said something that it would be secret they
information yes he he did not want to stand for them in interrogation
Eh yes there and then so he wanted them home
so to say so it was handled through tips but then it is enrolled in
because yes because, as I perceived from the investigator, that he was standing for the duties
later in [music]
the investigation eh you tell you that it was someone
a bag that was packed or were there several bags that were packed it was one
bag that stood outside with this TV then it was like
like a sheet that hung over there mm but they
here the mobile phones and shavers and so it was in
the bag it can't i remember eh i almost think it eh no
I can't remember if it was in the bag or if you wore them when
He just got into the apartment where etc. yes thank you then I have no more questions please
mm lawyer Olof lawyer Andersson No Thank you no then is over and we close
of
The recording and then the recording was up and then there is V interrogation here with
Evelina Å and it is the prosecutor who has a bät that you should be interrogated so that he
will get to start and ask questions to you and then so will the defendant
And then all the defense lawyers also get that opportunity here but
The prosecutor may start here please thank you hello hello this applies to an event then
On October 7, 2023 on OKQ8 South Malm Plan in Örebro Eh
It is about one about a person who then one who reported SK has bought eh gasoline on
dunk you know what I am talking about then eh i v a long time ago and a little hard to
remember but about yes ne but you can tell you what you remember only then then can
I fill up some questions then after you
told
said I can buy one that we have talked about this thunken prime crime dse yes yes
But that was the question of whether it was so I said so it was just that you give you
out dunkers if they ask for or is it so that you can buy it one
Instead, eh yes you can buy but sometimes it can stand empty cans
outside in the trash cans or so exactly that yes but I understand
ehm he asked if we had TMA cans on the layer glycol when found outside
The garbage can stand it s is something that sounds familiar
Mm yes it is difficult to remember it is so
long see and mm you have a lot of customers and mm so you have someone do you have any
Feeling for whether it deals with any more bottle or can than just the one that
you sell at the station
No no h
As it stands here I said he can buy empty cans and then he took
a f liter thunk and asked if one could bring
[Music]
glycol poisoned with the police where we can tune in a little neighbor did you tell
that you remembered then or is it something that you kept in with or that you laid
to as you remember no I had looked at
video movie mhm okay so d had you fished up the memory
before then before yes okay yes but then so and when did you see that movie and were
the same day you talked to the police or was it before at some time eh no
a little neighbor here I stood at the checkout and checked that he refueled and that he
Went from there people usually tell why you think up thumps for example to
they got a motor stop or similar I got feeling that he was not injured f that
fill up a car it was a bit more but that so it recorded it can be true
Lucky yes I don't know why I had that feeling it's hard to remember
Why I thought so no exactly yes because it says Kän also then only a foam
Feeling and I remembered he stuck out so it maybe a little there later
Have you been asked yes sorry then have asked if you have seen the man
Before, you remember what v you answer to that
No yes the answer was that you had not seen him before then one last thing here
Actually eh
that that read and approved this for the ear that a telephone interview also has
you have you memory that you talk to with the police about this
that they yes v you will ih call before mm yes okay yes but then so then it is not
any fl mm should we see if may ask here no thanks
no questions no then the lawyers f possibly here no
no no then the hearing is out and we turn off
The recording then was in place and then it is Vikne's interrogation here with Abdul Fat
Said and it is the prosecutor who sits here who has requested you to be heard so
he will start asking questions and then the plaintiff will be the same
Opportunity and all the defense lawyers in turn here but the prosecutor gets
Start please thank you very much the hello eh is the abd barrel you call it or
are you called abdi i call abdi okay we'll use it absolutely it was
well thank you ab I understand it as you drive taxi yes and this applies to one
Taxi ride that will be done then October 7, 2023 from the Central Station you have
have been a police interview regarding this incident do you remember which I which
out eh no it was a girl and a guy a girl and a guy okay just that
ehm you remember if there was something special about any of the people you
thought of like no no i took them as van was traveling i knew
I don't know v So what they have is what they do yes just that exactly that I
understands but they exactly what they jump off at the gas station there in til said you eh in
the beginning and then the you see on the map how I have driven do US turn
also eh by state or at the petrol station just that yes just that do you have any memory
By whom paid this taxi ride no I don't really remember no but I
Do she thinks that made up paid or or I don't really remember but I
Think she who put forward gave me money okay and when you say gave you money PR
Attaching cash then or yes I told them you can pay with short craft
Swish yes but they did not have briefly they had in cash with them
That page 32 and then we are
on the EH middle of the paragraph that is after the first question
Then you have described how you come to Seeking K anyway
ehm drops them so bes that she pays for the taxi yes it was true va
ehm after the woman has paid me so she handed money back to the guy and
says something in the style of you can keep the money standing this is would direct
over money to the guy in the car no I will not h no eh it was long see
I don't remember I can't sit here and g I don't remember you don't remember
That is calm but I but I think like this now when you talked to the police
Then October 17th you think you are better mines then than you do today what did you say
When you talked to the police here for what we f police interrogation and it was 17
sat down she talked on the phone she had phone in hand etc. as i mins
Just that yes but this person sitting behind was quiet he was quiet I remember
It was you were you person I said marte nothing
No you remember anything about what she was talking about on the phone no I remember
not no because you have received a question too is it at late 33 and then it stood
So here she talked about something if someone had spun money I didn't hear that
a lot yes i didn't hear okay i talked on the phone she she said eh like me
mins something if someone had taken h money or she has taken h reach as I
don't really remember but if s okay yes just that and then you said you don't have that
Very check it was ordinary customers for you who paid and were not stuck but
Did you say you had been asked this way what did you get for the feeling of the people and then
she paid by what do you mean by you can pay SEK 250 in different ways edge we
spoke 200 200 and then 50 kpp yes almost in
The hearing on page 303 you get asked how paid the woman
And the guy for the trip then it is in cash I got 100 100 20 20 SEK yes
I think I don't really remember yes it can be so 100 dogs yes because she
asked Afta gear yes I remember now yes she asked decrease gear I had gear
Yes but good it is fully understandable yes remember eh when you meet these
the people at the central and they and they eh book the trip or explain where they
Should you say you should go toward Duble, you remember what the woman says about she
leaving any address or similar no they did not book taxi it came from
Press agency kept eh and since we stood we i don't know if you've been to the central
It stood like taxis and since I was the farthest away
last k just but to you the woman said any address or similar no they said
How they expressed eh first they said in Til and then changed the ones I think I
think maybe they don't recognize how Örebro is eh as soon as we arrived at
The petrol station where they saw eh said they can you can you stay over there
Just that I had to stay then when you don't fully remember I would like to read
what you say at the bottom of page 32 it's almost the last line before one one
Ask coming there then it says like this she said something with helmets but I
are helmets, of course we get exactly the helmets the way this one goes up just
It yes so it was there may have been that she has mentioned helmets or helmets
the road or something so i good they are two in the car they talk to each other no like me
said she talked on the phone yes eh the other person sat back was quiet just yes you
Don't hear anything talking to each other during the trip no no yes thank you it was mine
questions etc. Thank you so much then before end we turn off recording
We do this even now and then the recording was up and then is
the witness's foreweck with Morgan Boje and it is the prosecutor who sits here who has Bärt
That you will be interrogated so he will start asking questions and then will
goals enter and all the defenders here in turn are given the opportunity to set
Questions but go may start please thank you hello eh you should be heard about two things
Actually the first is about the observation on Tulegatan 28 then so
it is also about the arrest of Hamads Vanan then as S to PM about but if we
Starting with in TNA on Tat 28 so I would like you to tell yourself what you
do there and what you see at the site eh I work as an intervention scout
thus fully civilly dressed but also intervenes as intervention police eh in our
service we work primarily against serious violent crimes and drug offenses in
the foundation the assignment we received was that a family or address could be risky
for any kind of act of violence I did not know exactly what they could become
exposed to but they had some kind of threat picture of themselves
Eh i together with my colleagues [music]
locked eh just there we react because eh you live there or are visiting so should
man v know them if it eh is unlocked eh this man is then between
Gate 28 and 30 for a long time frequently he stands and eh pills with his
phone and smoke eh yes you feel nervous he rarely stands he goes
back and forth and eh yes but we react to him
eh then on one occasion when he stands the poet's gate at 28an eh or very
Close to connection, there will be two Soss secretaries later but at this stage
do we only see two women to go to this gate so they go toward 28an and
Then when they see this man so they turn o and go away a few hundred
meters and we didn't really understand what happened there but in conjunction with it
calls in to 112 a call from the social services that two women have thought
go into the gate but they thought this man felt uncomfortable mm
eh so it confirmed like our feeling that this man behaves
differently on the spot
eh the women go from there without and go into the gate man
continues to stay out of the gate and in conjunction with this during the evening has
We also seen a guy with a warning jacket who goes in and out of the gate eh several
times eh will mika throw and in and out and when we we judged him as a
accommodation at at the address and on one occasion then this guy comes
With with warning jacket eh and then start talking to this one
the man standing outside eh we don't know what was said between
But they only exchanged a few words and then the notice of the eh lined man in
the gate and this unknown guy go after into the gate
eh so we interpreted as he was talking to him and asks if he could hang
me in simply m then takes about 10o minutes eh I want to remember eh and
Then this guy comes out again eh and he sits on his bike and ride
from the place you before leaving this one
The sequence you have to find out about how we this bike is locked or
unlocked it so safely in pm if i have seen that observation or not eh it
stands in PMet the second last paragraph San 38 here yes
that okay so you just fish the witness his memory here as he goes out from Aden locks
up the bike and Å from the site went up to the university hall then it is good
I have written the PM to direct connection so I can refer to it
Eh he cycles from there eh we get assignments from those who own
the effort that we should not control him so he disappears to unknown
place then the hours go during the night and really nothing else is observed as
have with the case to do eh i'm just going to get off my pass eh
and other colleagues will take on and exactly when we have largely
landed, I hear the effort that it becomes an intervention by a person
Just that and then in a chat that we have, the gripping photos are placed directly on
This arrested man and I shake to directly that it is identical upholstery
eh and body constitution size eh and so on the man we
have observed eh eh so i my spontaneous feeling was that yes he must have been there
To raise simply that was how we judged you saw when there was any picture
on the bike also yes exactly and the same with the bike was a dark d bike I want to
Remember that was well in line with the one we had seen okay yes but great
Eh that was probably what I had in that part it was good eh since then should only
change pm here eh so have you been involved as I
understood it in the arrest of Ham's al side out in Bengtsfors that is true
is right eh then i would like to know a little neighbor how the inland is included and
What I am particularly interested in is like how mobile phone is handled etc. EH
We get assignments there that Hamsa should be arrested EH as suspected in this case eh
I probably didn't know exactly participation there and then and eh in these cases get
We often to it is very important with the information found
in the phone they use encrypted chats so that it is usually eh
as we judged friend or a man and they start jogging down toward a bus stop in
Close connection to the home address eh my two colleagues
eh stops eh hamsa eh identifies as a police officer
and eh in conjunction with that I see that he
holding the phone in hand so I take it away from him because there is a decision about
that it should seize mm Eh so I take the phone sand with it identifying
themselves as police officers and eh we keep him eh it will be very like a multi -art
As soon as we take the phone and they grab him so he sits to
Physically counter -defense simply eh I exhibit the phone I see that
It is Face ID thus one it is unlocked with with face recognition
eh so i show off the phone to him and ask if it is his phone he
says yes it is my phone and then he immediately realizes that the phone is holding
on and unlocked which makes him close and grimace the face and
Why do you want to get into my phone and
eh no i have sensitive pictures there or yes here it was on in a second decision
so it really was struggle for life not to unlock the phone m it I
understands is that he he really just closed because then you can't access
Face recognition yes close your eyes and pushes the face into
his own jacket and then pushes his head toward their own knees before he
sitting in bus place just that okay no no more superficial thanks mm nice booklund no
thanks ol no Andersson no thanks no then the interrogation is over and we bed off
Recording so then the supplementary interrogation here with Leon Chag Rustic Eh and
Then K will have the opportunity to ask questions here please thank you so much yes Leon we heard
before from the witness Mats Rossin that it was possible to open this gate without a
take that one could have a credit card or something that thought before that
unlock it for other bit injuries there is something you knew when you were
on site
Thank you Prima Crime Defense Ask some questions no thank you no of the others
the defenders no we for the end and we turn off